github.com/tessapower linkedin.com/in/tessa-power www.tessapower.xyz

Tessa Power

CONTACT

 $\begin{array}{lll} \textbf{Address} & \textbf{Round Rock, TX 78681} \\ \textbf{Phone} & (512) \ 949\text{-}7235 \\ \textbf{Email} & \underline{\text{hello@tessapower.xyz}} \\ \end{array}$

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (CS) GPA: 3.6

- 2022 2024: Victoria University of Wellington, New Zealand
- 2020 2022: Massey University, New Zealand

Additional coursework

 2017 - 2018: Mechatronics at Baden-Württemberg Cooperative State University, Germany

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages:
 - ► Primary: C/C++ (7 yrs), Java (5 yrs), GLSL/HLSL
 - Working knowledge: Python, Ruby, TypeScript/JavaScript
- Graphics/Engine Development:
 DirectX 11, OpenGL, OpenCV, Win32,
 ImGui, ECS architectures, Shader authoring
- Backend & Dev-Ops: Node.js, Ruby on Rails, API design, AWS, CI/CD (Travis, Circle CI, GitHub Actions)
- Testing: CTest, Microsoft Unit Testing Framework (C++), GTest, JUnit, Cucumber, Jest, RSpec, Cypress
- Tools: Visual Studio, JetBrains IDEs, Git, Jira, Confluence, Slack, FFMPEG
- Methodologies: Agile/Scrum, TDD/BDD, CI/CD, Remote-first collaboration

SUMMARY

Versatile C/C++ & Java engineer specializing in computer graphics and game/rendering engines. Experienced with low-level systems, and delivering production-ready full-stack apps. Excels in writing performant, clean code, and working collaboratively as part of remote teams.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer I

Shuttlerock Limited | May 2021 - Jan 2022

- Extended in-house Ruby-on-Rails + React/TypeScript video review platform used with global clients.
- Refined web-based markup tools to streamline asynchronous client approvals and feedback across time zones.
- Championed automated UI-testing initiative, architecting a BDD regression suite with QA testing lead.

Developer Intern

Tatou Technologies Limited | Jun 2020 - Dec 2020

- Modernized Ruby-on-Rails + Typescript web app and React Native mobile app test suites.
- Boosted automated test coverage and reduced time to deploy with automated regression test suites.
- Created end-user app tutorial videos and docs reducing support requests and onboarding time.

Product Associate

YR Live Limited | Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

- \bullet Co-defined the product vision and road map collaboratively with the CTO/Co-founder.
- Introduced Agile culture (Scrum ceremonies), dissolved communication silos with company-wide Slack, accelerating project cadence across Japan/US/UK teams.
- Partnered with clients to pioneer on-demand, online store integrations for sustainable, low-waste custom-print apparel production lines.

PROJECTS

3D Editable Mesh Terrain GitHub Link 3D terrain simulation, C++, OpenGL, GLSL, procedural generation, real-time rendering/mesh editing, ImGui.

DX11 Rendering Engine GitHub Link Hardware-accelerated rendering engine, C, C++, DirectX 11, Win32, HLSL, custom shader development, ImGUI.

2D Game Engine GitHub Link 2D game engine, Java, ECS architecture, rendering, audio, 2D physics, collision-overlap detection.